Melodie Irvin

2202 W. North Loop Blvd. #334., Austin, TX 78756

Phone: (713) 548-7256 E-Mail: melodie.k.irvin@gmail.com

Summary

Pre-veterinary student enthusiastic about gaining hands-on clinical experience in caring for and assisting animals. Duties to include, but not be limited to: providing treatment for hospitalized animals, obtaining urine/fecal/blood samples from various animals and preparing them for laboratory testing, providing love and compassion, administering treatments, and general cleaning duties involved in obtaining the position of Veterinary Technician .

Experience

Affordable Pet Care Veterinary Technician Assistant

August 2017 - October 2018

- Assisted veterinarian in surgical procedures, restraint, and gathering relevant patient information.
- Drew blood for in-house testing as well as administered medications and vaccinations to cats and dogs.
- Checked in patients for surgical procedures.
- Packed and autoclaved surgery packs.
- Took inventory of all medications and specialty food.

Austin Vet Hospital Shadow to Veterinarian and Vet Technicians

April 2017 – August 2017

- Assisted Veterinary Technicians with restraints and drawing blood.
- Observation of spay and neuter surgeries, dental cleanings, blood draws, veterinary technician intake of patient history, as well as catheter insertion.

Austin Pets Alive! Volunteer

November 2016 - Present

- Assisted LVTs with input of patient's information into Shelter Luv computer program, weighing of dogs, and administration of injections as well as oral medication.
- Assisted Ringworm Ward Manager with administration of medication and care for kittens with calicivirus and ringworm.

Decker Elementary School Special Education Teacher

August 2015 - June 2017

- Maintained open communication with parents and teachers about well-being and progress of students
- Created and focused on achieving and monitoring attainable goals for students with special needs.

Education

University of Texas at Austin

January 2019-December 2020

• Seeking post-baccalaureate degree in Biology with pre-veterinary track.

University of Texas at Austin

August 2009 - May 2012

- Bachelor of Science in Radio-Television-Film
- GPA: 3.1/4.0

University of Texas at San Antonio

August 2008 – May 2009

- CAP Program: Liberal Arts Student
- GPA: 3.3/4.0

Skills

Precision with blood draws from jugular and cephalic veins of dogs and cats

Ability to restrain animals using Fear Free techniques

Knowledge of Avimark software

Attention to Detail

Clear and consistent oral and written communication

Interpersonal communication

Knowledge of R-Studio